Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 12 -- Letters from Franklin 1733-1789 Mss.B.F85inventory12
American Philosophical Society
- Letters from Benjamin Franklin
  - to [Jean Baptiste] Le Roy., 1769 September 22; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Has sent him one of the achromatic glasses complete, also three of the glasses described in one of his printed letters. The astronomers knew nothing before his return of the comet he [Le Roy] told him about at Paris; they have since watched it very closely, but as the French astronomers have observed it three weeks sooner, he supposes they have been better able to determine its orbit. (Mutilated.)
  - to [Barbeu] Dubourg., 1769 September 22; A. Dr. of L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Sends him some sheets of his piece now printing and requests him to make any corrections. Sends him [Joseph] Priestley's essay on the First Principles of [Government].
    Printed in Works (Smyth, V, 229).
  - to [Thomas François] Dalibard., 1769 September 22; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Thanks him for the many civilities and marks of friendship he received from him and Mad. Dalibard while in Paris. Sends him an engraving of himself.
    Printed in Works (Smyth, V, 230).
  - to John Winthrop., 1769 March 11; A. Dr. of L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Has obtained a telescope for him. Sent the new edition of his Philosophical Papers to Harvard College; the resolutions to consume no more British goods, if persisted in, may have a good effect another year.
    Printed in Works (Bigelow, IV, 233; Smyth V, 198).
  - to William Strahan., 1769 November 29; L.S. 8p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Dr. Franklin's opinion of how the supremacy of the Legislature may be best preserved. Answers to Mr. [William] Strahan's queries. What he fears is like to come to pass.
    (Copy in French.)
    Printed in Works (Smyth, V, 237).
  - Memoranda., [1769.]; 8p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relative the Alderman [Barlow] Trecothic[k]'s character; cruelty in starving the poor; his humbug alphabet; orders for paper. Memoranda concerning prisoners; [John Paul] Jone's squadron, etc., etc.
  - to Editor of -----., [1769.]; A. Dr. of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Rebukes M.S. for abusing the New Englanders in his attempt to defend Lord Hillbororough's conduct. Comments on the disagreeable consequences that may result from it. (Incomplete.)
  - Rise and Present State of the Misunderstanding with North America and the Effect of the Non-importation Resolutions., [1769?]; A. Dr. of Diss. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin. Philadelphia., 1770 March 18; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Is well. Mrs. [Margaret] Stevenson and Polly send their affections.
  - to [Mrs. Deborah Franklin]., 1770 June 10; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Told sally [Franklin] Sir John Pringle's opinion as to the probability of her son not having the small-pox hereafter; he advised that since no eruption appeared, to make sure of the thing by inoculating him again. His health.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 449; Bigelow, IV, 348; Smyth, V, 264).
  - to ------ -----., [1770.] June 15; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Is going out of town but will endeavor to return in time for the pleasure be proposes to him to meet Baron Behr. Asks him to advise Mr. [Richard] Jackson, if he should be at a loss how to get ashore the two barrels of flour that came from Philadelphia. Informs him that one barrel of flour is for him. Mr. [John] Foxcroft's high opinion of the flour.
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin, Philadelphia., 1770 July 19; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    This letter will be delivered by their countryman, Mr. [Henry] Benbridge; he has so greatly improved in Italy as a portrait painter that the connoisseurs think few or none excel him; hopes he will meet with encouragement in his own country and that they do not lose him as they lost Mr. [Benjamin] West. He chose Pennsylvania merely from affection for that State; could live exceedingly well in England by his profession.
  - to Dennis De Berdt, Agent for the Assembly of the Massachusetts Bay., [1770. September?]; A.L.S. "The Publick," 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In the Gazetteer of Friday, August 26, he states that the repost insinuating that the Earl of Hillsborough had neglected to deliver a petition from the Assembly of Masschusetts Bay to His Majesty, was groundless; glad he set the matter right. Hopes he will also be able to refute the statement that his Lordship having an account of the purport of the Assembly's petition, refused to receive it from him on the ground that he was not a regularly appointed Agent consented to by the Governor. Asks him for the reasons he gave the Assembly for not proceeding with their petition.
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin, Philadelphia., 1770 October 3; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Benjamin Franklin Bache. Story of two little boys in a street. Is sorry he did not send one of his books to Mr. Rhodes since he was desirous of seeing it.
    Printed in Works, (Sparks, VII, 487; Bigelow, IV, 368; Smyth, V, 282).
  - to The Craven Street Gazette., [1770.]; A. Dr. of L. 5p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Satirical communication. (Incomplete.)
    Printed in Works (sparks, II, 236; Begelow, IV, 361; Smyth, V, 277).
  - Memorandum., [1770.]; A. Mem. 5p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relating to the various complaints of Dr. [William] H[unter] against Mr. William H[ewson]'s conduct.
  - to Lord ------ ------., A. Dr. of L. Endorsed. "Rough draft." Letter for Bourke, French Master. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Has a just demand on one of his officers, Mr. Eyles, Warden of the Fleet, which he refuses to satisfy. Too poor to go to law, therefore applies to His Lordship's goodness to be informed of the case and to do him justice.
  - Memoranda., A. Mem. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Dates of setting out and return of journeys in 1766, 1767 and 1769.
  - to [Mrs. Deborah Franklin]., 1771 January 2; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Acknowledges the receipt of her letters.
  - to William Franklin., 1771 April 20; A. Dr. of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Severe winter. [Thomas] Walpole's grant. The Acts of the New Jersey Assembly; accounts with his son. (Incomplete.)
    Printed, in part, in Works [Sparks, VII, 516; Bigelow, IV, 394; Smyth, V, 313).
  - to Humphry Marshall, West Bradford, Pa., 1771 April 22; A.L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Encouragement of home manufacturers.
    (Facsimile.)
    Printed in Works (Bigelow, X, 315; Smyth, V, 315).
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin, Philadelphia., 1771 May 1; A.L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Received the bill for £30 on Sir Alexander Grant; sorry she had so much trouble in buying it, especially as it occasioned her some disgust against Messrs. [John and Thomas] Foxcroft for not supplying the money to pay for it. He had limited them in their payments to her to the sum of £30 per month, for the sake of thier more easily settling and to prevent mistakes. Does not like her going around among his friends to borrow money with which to buy bills and asks her to decline buying them in the future. Will order more money to be given her if she will satisfy him that what she receives is insufficient. Is pleased with the little histories of the fine boy.
  - to Thomas Pownall., 1771 May 8; A. Dr. of L. in 3d P. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. Craven Street
    Thinks Mr. Sargent of Downing Street corresponds with Mr. [Daniel] Coxe, [5th], and will probably take out the warrant [appointing him one of the Council of New Jersey. See Vol. I, p. 120.]
  - to Isaac Smith., 1771 May 17; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. Craven Street
    Rule to be observed in travelling through foreign countries.
    Printed in Works (Smyth, V, 320).
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin, Philadelphia., 1771 June 5; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Made a journey of a fortnight to Birmingham, Sheffield, Leeds and Manchester. The King's birthday. Feels exceedingly well.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 524; Bigelow, IV, 401; Smyth, V, 321).
  - to [Jonathan Shipley], Bishop of St. Asaph., 1771 June 24; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Visit at Twyford. Sends a book to Miss Georgiana and a specimen of American dried apples for Mrs. Shipley.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 524; Bigelow, IV, 402; Smyth, V, 329).
  - to [Jonathan Shipley], Bishop of St. Asaph., 1771 July 25; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Should have been happy in accompanying His Lordship on that agreeable party, or in being in Twyford instead of being in London. Proposes to set out next Tuesday, if nothing prevents.
    Printed in Works (Smyth, V, 337).
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin, Philadelphia., 1771 July 4; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Is well; will write more fully by next pacquet.
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin, Philadelphia., 1771 July 4; A.L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Hopes her cold is gone; cure for a cold. Accident to Mr. Rogers and his family. If he were to build again would make his house incapable of burning. Remarks about his grandson. Will return after another winter. Sends her two plated canisters and a sugar canister.
  - to [Mrs. Deborah Franklin]., 1771 August 14; A.L. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    His pictures. Visit to the Bishop of St. Asaph's family. Will set out on a trip to Ireland with his old friend, Counsellor [Richard] Jackson. Desires her to push the enquiry after the Lancaster Dutchman and not let it sleep and be forgotten. (Concluding part mutilated.)
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 538; Bigelow, IV, 415; Smyth, V, 338).
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin, Philadelphia., 1771 August 17; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Continues well, but finds more exercise necessary to preserve his health. About to make the tour of Ireland with Mr. [Richard] Jackson, and return through Scotland before the Parliament opens. Would not have her send the receipts for the money she pays, but it would be agreeable to him to see from time to time an account of the considerable sums. Introduces Mr. Tyler, who wishes to settle in Philadelphia. Has spent three weeks with his friend the Bishop [of St. Asaph]. Promised to spend the Christmas holidays with him.
  - to ----- -----., [1771?] August 15; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    His cash is lower than usual. After examining his accounts he finds that he cannot, without the greatest inconvenience to himself, comply with his request.
  - Agreement., 1771 December 18; A.D.S. B[enjamin] Franklin, Joseph Massie.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relative to an extension of time to fulfill the conditions of a certain transaction.
  - List of Papers Relating to the Affairs of Georgia., [1771.]; A. Mem. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Received in a parcel.
  - to [Mrs. Jane Mecom]., 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Draft of the two concluding paragraphs and postscripts.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 541; Bigelow, IV, 428; Smyth, V, 348).
  - to Mrs. [Elizabeth] Partridge., 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Received her "angry-a-little" letter though he "had suffered a preceiding one to remain two years unanswered." If he did so, which he doubts, he begs to be excused. (Incomplete.)
  - to S[amuel] Frankliln., 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    How to choose a wife. Just returned from a long journey through Wales, Ireland, Scotland and the Northern parts of England.
    Printed, in part, in Works, (Sparks, VII, 559; Bigelow, IV, 446; in full, Smyth, V, 370).
  - to Caty Greene?, 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L.S.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Sends a receipt for making cheese and hopes that she may be the means of introducing a valuable manufacture into the country-the more valuable, as the as cream is saved and hence the farm affords more butter; as the same time that the cheese is of so much greater value. Bids her not to be discouraged and send a piece of right Parmesan that she may be acquainted with it, and know when she has hit it.
  - to Mr. Ware Gov[erno]r., 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Thanks him for recommending Mr. Marchant to him had the pleasure of his company in Scotland and will do what he can to serve him. Condoles with him on the loss of his amiable partner. Hopes he will find comfort in his children.
  - to Dr. [Ezra] Stiles., 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Zoroaster's writtings in French. Remarks on the work.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 559; Bigelow, IV, 447; Smyth, V, 371).
  - to Dr. [Joshua] Babcock., 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Agricultural pursuits. Condition of the poor in Ireland. Happiness of the New England people. Benefits of civilization.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 552; Bigelow, IV, 439; Smyth, V, 361).
  - to [James] Bowdoin., 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L.S. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Dr. [Joseph] Priestley. Lord Grenville's sentiment respecting American affairs. Colonial Agents in England. Dined with Mr. [Charles] Lucas in Ireland.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 549; Bigelow, IV, 436; Smyth, V, 358).
  - to Dr. [Samuel] Cooper., 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L.S. 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Reason why the Governors should be paid by the Provincial Legislature rather than the Crown. Commissioners should not be exempt from the payment of taxes. Commodore [James] Gambier. Shall continue to exert himself in behalf of his country whether he is rechosen Agent or not. Anecdote.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 545; Bigelow, IV, 432; Smyth, V, 354).
  - to [Prof. John] Winthrop., 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Received the 52 shillings. Hopes Mr. Winthrop received the Transactions for 1770. Will forward the new volume as soon as it arrives. Wants to know whether he should give the paper he enclosed to him to the [Royal] Society.
  - to Tho[ma]s Cushing., 1772 January 13; A. Dr. of L. 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Tour in Ireland. Visit to Lord Hillsborough, his extraordinary civilities and his sentiments on American affairs. Introduced to the Irish Parliament. (Incomplete.)
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 554; Bigelow, IV, 441; Smyth, V, 363).
  - to [Anthony] Tissington., 1772 January 28; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Received his turkey and drank to his and Mrs. Tissington's health. Mrs. [Margaret] Stevenson is ailing with rheumatic pains. Sorry he could not call at Alfreton.
    Printed in Works (Smyth, V, 375).
  - to [Mrs. Deborah Franklin]., 1772 January 28; A.Dr. of L.S. 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Pleased with the little history of his grandson. Advised Mr. [Richard] Bache to settle down to business in Philadelphia, to deal in the ready money way only; has given him £200 to add something to his cargo. Received neighbor Haddock's silk and carried it to her relations. The squirrels, buckwheat, Indian meal, dried peaches and apples came to hand, but the sturgeon did not arrive. Sends her a piece of Holland from Ireland.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 561; Bigelow, IV, 448, Smyth, V, 372).
  - to [Mrs. Sarah Bache]., 1772 January 29; A. Dr. of L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Met Mr. [Richard] Bache at Preston and advised him to settle down in business in Philadelphia. Advice to his daughter. Pleased that the things sent proved agreeable.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 563; Bigelow, IV, 451; Smyth, V, 376).
  - to [William Franklin]., 1772 January 30; A. Dr. of L.S. 6p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Lord Hillsborough's civilities. A tour in Ireland. Lord Hillsborough's opinion of the obnoxious treatment of the Colonies. Introduced into the Irish Parliament. Trip through Scotland. Mr. [Richard] Bache's desire. American Agents in England. Proposes returning home.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 564; Bigelow, IV, 452; Smyth, V, 378).
  - Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin, Philadelphia., 1772 February 3; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Continues well, and hopes they are also well.
  - to [William Franklin]., 1772 February 3; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Recommends the Rev. Mr. [Thomas] Coombe; not only an excellent preacher, but practices the morality he preaches. Parliament opened with a calm in party affairs. Peace seems about restored between the Turks and Russians.
  - to [John] Foxcroft., 1772 February 4; A. Dr. of L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Common error in friends to make comparisons and depreciate the merits of others. Not necessary to do so in this case. Mr. [Samuel] Wharton will have a good deal of merit in the affair [the Walpole grant] if it succeeds, he having been exceedingly active and industrious in it. But though he [Dr. Franklin] has not been equally active his advice may have been thought of some use, since it has been asked on every step and he believes he has lent some weight to the negotiations by his joining in the affair, from the greater confidence men are apt to place in one they know than in a stranger. As he neither asks nor expects any particular consideration for any service he may have done, he only thinks he ought to escape censure. Let all do their endeavors in their special capacities, and if one has the ability or the opportunity of doing more for his friends than another, let him think that a happiness and be satisfied. The business is not yet completed and as many things happen between the cup and the lip perhaps there may be nothing of this kind for friends to dispute about. Adjustment of their private accounts.
  - to [John] Foxcroft., 1772 February 4; A. extract from this letter. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VIII, I; Bigelow, IV, 473; Smyth, V, 382).
  - to Dr. [Richard] Price., 1772 February 11; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Thanks him for his excellent book in which he appeals to the public on the subject of the National Debt.
    Printed in Works (Smyth, V, 389).
  - to Noble Wimberley Jones, 1772 April 2; A Dr. of L.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Hopes the petition relating to the controverted lands may be brought to a favorable conclusion before the closing of the House. Shall interview Governor [James Wright] on his arrival here, relative to his treatment of the Assembly and Mr. Jones. Relation of the Parliament to the King to facilitate intercourse. Comparison of the liberties taken by Kings and Governors. (Incomplete.)
    Printed in Works (Smyth, V, 390).
  - to ----- -----., 1772 April 3; A. Dr. of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. Craven Street
    Is of the opinion that Cook should be agreed with, notwithstanding the advance on what he once offered the right for. Dr. [Cadwalader] Evans thinks it worth double.
  - to ---- ----., 1772 April 3; A. Dr. of L. S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. Craven Street
    Tapped the porter and found it excellent; Mrs. [Margaret] Stevenson sends him some souns and tongues from America, with direction for dressing them.
  - to [Jean Baptiste] Le Roy, 1772 April 20; A. Dr. of L. S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Glad that he is happily married. Intended French Expedition to the North Pole. Messrs. Banks and Solander are to sail soon with two ships for the south; they expect to be out four years.
    Printed in Works (Bigelow, IV, 480; Smyth, V, 393).
  - to Dr. [Joseph] Priestley., 1772 May 4.; A. Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Dr. Franklin's electrical machine; the Abbé Nollet's machine. De Lor's machine. Le Roy has received an electrical machine which he has improved so as to produce the positive and negative electricities separately or together at the same time.
    Printed in Works (Bigelow, IV, 482; Smyth, V, 394)
  - to [John Foxcroft?], 1772 May 5; A. Dr. of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    The session of Parliament has been a quiet one and draws near a conclusion. Lord North manages ably. Peace is negotiating between the Turks and the Russionas, and miserable Poland is in a fair way of being pacified too. There is no present appearance of any other war likely to occur in Europe. Sir John Pringle has proposed to him a journay to Switzerland for the summer, but he has not resolved upon it. Proposes visiting America in the summer, if not returning for good and all. Will spend the summer in the country with his friends, if he does not visit America. (Mutilated.)
  - to [Mrs. Deborah Franklin], 1772 May 5; A. L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Is sorry for the disorder that has befallen his friend Mr. [Ebenezer] Kinnersley. Hopes Mr. [Richard] Bache is, by this time, home.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VII, 8; Bigelow, IV, 484; Smyth, V, 396).
  - To The Printer of the Public Advertiser, 1772 June 3; A. Dr. of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Reason for one sect persecuting another. Relative to the justice of the charge against the present dissenters, particularly those in America. (Incomplete.)
    Printed in Works (Sparks, II, 112; Bigelow, IV, 466; Smyth, V, 408).
  - to [Mrs. Deborah Franklin], 1772 July 14; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Visits to the North of England.
    Printed in Works (Sparks, VIII, 9; Bigelow, IV, 494; Smyth, V, 408)
  - Memorandum., 1772 February; A. Mem. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relative to his accounts with James Parker.
  - to [Mrs.] Deborah Franklin and Richard Bache., 1772 February 17; D.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. Philadelphia
    Power of attorney to his wife, Deborah, and son-in-law, Richard Bache.
  - to The Managers of the Contributions for Promoting the Culture of silk in Pennsylvania., 1772 February ?; A. Dr. of L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    In relation to silk culture in America and the waste of silk in dyeing. Peculiar customs in the silk trade. (First part missing.)
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin. Philadelphia., 1772 March 19; A.L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Is glad to hear that her kingbird [Benjamin Franklin Bache] has gone through his second inoculation. Sends her the curtains she wrote for. A new bedstead is being made. (Mutilated.)
  - Minutes of the Committee on the Purfleet Magazine, 1772 August 12; 1 p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Meeting attended by Mr. [Henry] Cavendish, Dr. Franklin, Dr. [William] Watson, Mr. Benjamin Wilson and Mr. [John] R[obertson]. Agreed that conductors to the magazine are necessary. How and where they should be placed.
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin, Philadelphia., 1772 August 22; A.L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Had a severe attack of the gout but is somewhat better. Mrs. [Benjamin] West has another son to whom he is godfather. His other godson, Billy Hewson, is a fine boy. Mr. [Alexander] Small returned home full of the praises of America. Rejoices that she had so much pleasure with her kingbird [Benjamin Franklin Bache].
  - to Observations on Pointed Lightning Rods., 1772 August 27; A. Dr. of Diss. 2p. (Fragment.); Franklin, Benjamin. London
    Relative to the size of conductors necessary to protect houses from lightning. (Incomplete.)
    (Fragment.)
    Printed in Works (Sparks, V, 435; Bigelow, IV, 508; Smyth, V, 420).
  - to [Duc de la Vallière]., 1772 September 4; A.Dr. of L.S. 1p. (With a French translation.); Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    With the greatest pleasure he received the information of his nomination by the King to fill a vacancy in the Academy of Sciences as Associé étranger; begs him to present to His Majesty his grateful acknowledgments.
    (With a French translation.)